A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Business Interests, Series C FA312
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Center, Inc. (RCI)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Organization, 1929-1953 (Box 75, Folder 563)
    Organization of Metropolitan Square Corporation; delegation of authority. Changes in certificate of incorporation; change of name to Rockefeller Center, Inc.. Changes in By-laws. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    205.1
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Organization - Certificate of Incorporation, By-Laws, 1928-1953 (Box 75, Folder 0563A)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Corporation - Miscellaneous Contracts, 1930-1935 (Box 75, Folder 564)
    205.12
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Insurance, 1932-1944 (Box 75, Folder 565)
    Plans for self insurance; proposals of insurance companies; selection of agents. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, Thomas M. Debevoise, Gus Eyssell, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    205.2
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Insurance, 1945-1952 (Box 75, Folder 566)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Tax Foundation, 1938-1946 (Box 76, Folder 567)
    Foundation organized to fight rising governmental costs at state and local level; Rockefeller Center, Inc. a subscriber. Correspondence with Citizens Public Expenditure Survey. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, B. P. Turnbull, Phillip Keebler.
    205.3A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Tax Foundation, 1947-1949 (Box 76, Folder 568)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - 1945 Depreciation and Leasehold Amortization, 1940-1950 (Box 76, Folder 569)
    Negotiations with federal government over rate of depreciation of buildings. Settlement proposed by government accepted by Center directors. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Phillip Keebler, B. P. Turnbull.
    205.3B
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Corporation - Taxes, 1929-1949 (Box 76, Folder 570)
    Income, real estate, employees; organization of capital stock, structure to meet tax requirements. Assessments. Correspondents include B. P. Turnbull, Phillip Keebler, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    205.3
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Corporation - Taxes, 1950-1961 (Box 76, Folder 571)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Purchases, 1928-1930 (Box 77, Folder 572)
    Adding to columbia leasehold; reports of purchases to Executive Committee. Correspondents include F. T. Christy, Charles O. Heydt.
    205.4
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Purchases, 1931-1938 (Box 77, Folder 573)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Wendel Property - 70 West 51st Street, 1930-1935 (Box 77, Folder 574)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Property - 8 West 49th Street, 1932-1945 (Box 77, Folder 575)
    Leasing of property; discussion re possible tenants; use of building. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    205.41
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Property - 8 West 49th Street - Restrictive Covenants, 1936 (Box 77, Folder 576)
    Releases of covenants.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Property - 8 West 49th Street - Sale to Centroc, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 577)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. sale to subsidiary of Rockefeller Center.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Property - 8 West 49th Street - Purchase, 1929-1934 (Box 77, Folder 578)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s purchase of 8 West 49th.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - 50th Street and 6th Avenue, Inc., 1952-1956 (Box 77, Folder 579)
    Purchase of land for new Time-Life Buliding; settlement of tax questions. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler.
    205.42
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown), 1929-1947 (Box 78, Folder 580)
    1929, John R. Todd's firm hired as project managers; compensation; progress. Referrals to Todd and Brown from Rockefeller office. Construction; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest in architecture and gardens. Arrangements of tenants and decorators; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s comments on buildings. Hugh S. Robertson appointed executive manager. Personal relations between J. R. Todd and Rockefellers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John R. Todd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt.
    205.5
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown), 1929-1947 (Box 78, Folder 581)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown), 1929-1947 (Box 78, Folder 582)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown), 1929-1947 (Box 78, Folder 583)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown) - Survey of Pedestrian Traffic - Rockefeller Center, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 584)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown) - Agreements, Documents, 1929-1934 (Box 78, Folder 585)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd Robertson (Brown) - Sandbar Agreement, 1929-1933 (Box 78, Folder 586)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agreed to help finance building; not built; deal cancelled.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd and Brown - 1936 Contract, 1936-1938 (Box 78, Folder 587)
    Renewal of contract; discussions of provisions by Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Rockefellers' objections; resignation of J. M. Todd from Board of Managers. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Not Used (Box 78, Folder 588)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd-Robertson - Cash Requirements, 1930-1934 (Box 79, Folder 589)
    Initial figures of cost of development; building progress; requirements for funds as called for by builders. Funds from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Metropolitan Life. Adjustments in construction leading to budget changes; budget planning; procedures in handling of building funds. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John R. Todd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, H. Robertson.
    205.52
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Todd-Robertson - Cash Requirements, 1935-1944 (Box 79, Folder 590)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Estimates, Annual Appropriation, 1933-1942 (Box 79, Folder 591)
    Submission of annual budget to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for approval; discussion of budget; changes. Progress of construction, rental and use of Center. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., B. P. Turnbull, Charles O. Heydt.
    205.52A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Estimates, Annual Appropriation, 1943-1961 (Box 79, Folder 592)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Building #7, 1937-1938 (Box 79, Folder 593)
    Plans; estimates; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. approval. Progress; savings; became Associated Press Building. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. Robertson.
    205.53
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Building #7 - Contract with Hegeman Harris Company, Inc., 1938 (Box 79, Folder 594)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Building #11 - Suggestions Garage and Parking Space, 1938-1951 (Box 79, Folder 595)
    Garage; budget; planning construction. Operation; complaints. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    205.54
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Building #11 - Sidewalk Superintendents Club, 1938-1958 (Box 79, Folder 596)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Holland House, 1938-1939 (Box 80, Folder 597)
    Ideas for building; use of building. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, H. Robertson.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Building #8, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 598)
    Arrangements for construction. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    205.55
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - November 1, 1939 Completion of Buildings (Box 80, Folder 599)
    November 1, 1939 ceremony of driving last rivet by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; speeches; publicity; thanks from Nelson A. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to those who participated. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Merle Crowell.
    205.55A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - November 1, 1939 Completion of Buildings - Letters of Appreciation (Box 80, Folder 600)
    Appreciation for building Rockefeller Center.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - November 1, 1939 Completion of Buildings - Mr. Rockefeller's Address (Box 80, Folder 601)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - November 1, 1939 Completion of Buildings - Distribution of "Last Rivet", 1940 (Box 80, Folder 602)
    Account of rivet ceremony including speeches, distributed by Nelson A. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Thank-you letters from recipients, in alphabetical order.
    205.55A1
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - November 1, 1939 Completion of Buildings - Distribution of "Last Rivet" - Letters from Venezuelans, 1940 (Box 80, Folder 603)
    Spanish government officials.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Esso Building, 1941-June 1946 (Box 80, Folder 604)
    Lease arrangements with Standard Oil of New Jersey, Chemical Bank; permission for tunnel. Standard Oil's need for additional space. Rental costs; construction of building. Correspondents include H. Robertson, B. P. Turnbull, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    205.56
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Esso Building, 1946-1950 (Box 80, Folder 605)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Massachusetts Mutual Life Building, 1949 (Box 81, Folder 606)
    Proposal for 49th Street building; copies of agreements; no action. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise.
    205.57
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. (Metropolitan Square) - Sale to Opera Company, 1927-1934 (Box 81, Folder 607)
    Unsuccessful negotiations to bring opera company into Center. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Myron Taylor, Otto Kahn.
    205.6
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity, 1930-1935 (Box 81, Folder 608)
    Arrangements for special articles on Center; replacement of Ivy Lee by T. J. Ross. Applications for publicity positions; use of Helen Keller's letter for publicity. Promotional ideas; publicity policy; newspaper stories sent to Rockefellers by editors. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Merle Crowell.
    205.7
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity, 1936-1946 (Box 81, Folder 609)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity, 1947-1961 (Box 81, Folder 610)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity - Fortune Article, 1936 (Box 81, Folder 611)
    Galley proof.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity - Ivy Lee Correspondence, 1929-1946 (Box 81, Folder 612)
    Financial arrangements; selection of name.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity - Coronet Article by Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1955 (Box 81, Folder 613)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller signed photographic article.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity - Christmas Celebrations, 1933-1961 (Box 81, Folder 614)
    Publicity on tree and decorations.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publicity - Newspaper Clippings, 1928-1960 (Box 82, Folder 615)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Magazine, 1941-1942 (Box 82, Folder 616)
    Analysis of purpose and operation of magazine; discontinued due to World War II. 3 copies of "The Story of Rockefeller Center." Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Merle Crowell.
    205.71
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Magazine - Center Publications, Inc., 1934-1941 (Box 82, Folder 617)
    Corporation information; dissolved in 1949.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Periodical - "The Boulevard", 1953 (Box 82, Folder 0617A)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Publication - Rockefeller Center: A Photographic Narrative, 1947 (Box 82, Folder 0617B)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Rockefeller Center Weekly, 1934-1940 (Box 82, Folder 618)
    Rockefeller Center news, plans, problems, promotions; selection of feature articles. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Merle Crowell, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Rockefeller Center History, 1949-1950 (Box 82, Folder 619)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances, 1929-1950 (Box 83, Folder 620)
    Inter-company investments; building costs; upkeep records; purchase and sale of securities. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise, B. P. Turnbull, J. D. Dilworth.
    205.9
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances, 1951-1961 (Box 83, Folder 621)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Consolidated Oil Company Stock, 1935-1943 (Box 83, Folder 622)
    Voting proxies; sale of stock.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Ohio Oil Company Stock, 1935-1938 (Box 83, Folder 623)
    Sale of stock.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Re Notes, 1929-1931 (Box 83, Folder 624)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loans to Corporation.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Colorado Fuel and Iron, 1936-1945 (Box 83, Folder 625)
    Rockefeller Center, Inc. investment in Colorado Fuel and Iron securities.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Finance Committee Minutes, 1954-1961 (Box 83, Folder 626)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Stock, 1939-1943 (Box 83, Folder 627)
    Rockefeller Center, Inc. investment in stock.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Pinturas Tucan, 1954-1955 (Box 83, Folder 628)
    Rockefeller Center, Inc. investment in Venezuelan corporation.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Finances - Signing Checks, 1934-1960 (Box 83, Folder 629)
    Authorizations for signing checks drawn against Center.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Miscellaneous - Maps of Lands in City, 1859 (Box 83, Folder 630)
    1859 map of Center site.
    205.8
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Miscellaneous - Data, 1930-1932 (Box 83, Folder 631)
    Charles O. Heydt calculations on Center's cost.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Miscellaneous - Metropolitan Square Development - Miscellaneous Maps and Data, 1930-1932 (Box 83, Folder 632)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Miscellaneous - Photographs - Rockefeller Center, 1930-1932 (Box 83, Folder 633)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 634)
    File Plan
    205.91
    Restricted from scholarly access.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1959 (Box 84, Folder 635)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1960 (Box 84, Folder 636)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1961 (Box 84, Folder 637)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Correspondence re Financial Reports, 1941-1947 (Box 84, Folder 638)
    Interpretation of some of the figures.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Re Auditors, 1937-1960 (Box 84, Folder 639)
    Hiring of auditing firm; annual renewal of contract. Survey and modification of accounting program. Auditors fees; copy of 1960 audit.
    205.91A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Corporation - Financing, 1933-1944 (Box 85, Folder 640)
    Status of gold clause in Rockefeller Center, Inc. bonds; payment of Mr. Tanner; 1944 indenture. Correspondence includes Thomas M. Debevoise.
    205.92
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Corporation - Financing - Rockefeller Institute Loan, 1931 (Box 85, Folder 641)
    Re Rockefeller Institute loan to Columbia of $8,000,000; copy of mortgage and bond; assignment of mortgage to Chase Manhattan.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Financing - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1931-1934 (Box 85, Folder 642)
    Arrangement of terms of loan from Insurance Company; purchase of bonds; retirement of bonds. Correspondence includes John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur Woods.
    205.92A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Financing - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1935-1950 (Box 85, Folder 643)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Financing - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company - Mortgage Negotiations, 1940 (Box 85, Folder 644)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Metropolitan Square Financing - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company - Agreements, 1931-1947 (Box 85, Folder 645)
    Loan agreement between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Insurance Company.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Guarantees and Commitments, 1928-1933 (Box 86, Folder 646)
    Copy of 1928 John D. Rockefeller, Jr.-Columbia agreement; lease and agreements with Metropolitan Square Corporation. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.-Metropolitan Life Insurance Company agreement; 1931 Indenture, Amendment to Lease, 1930 Amendment to lease. List of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. commitments and guarantees.
    205.93
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Financial Information and Budget Committee, 1935-1961 (Box 86, Folder 647)
    Correspondence re Committee's work; list of Rockefeller Center, Inc. contributions and scholarship program gifts. No 1938-1959 material. Correspondents include Jay Downer, B. P. Turnbull, Phillip Keebler.
    205.94
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Gift of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Notes to Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1952-1955 (Box 86, Folder 648)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $60,000,000 Rockefeller Center, Inc. notes to Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, Dana S. Creel.
    205.96
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Recapitalization of Stock, 1954-1955 (Box 86, Folder 649)
    Increase in stock from $1,000 at $1 a share. Tax problems; distribution of new stock. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Thomas M. Debevoise, J. E. Lockwood, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    205.97
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Recapitalization of Stock - Columbia Agreement, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 650)
    Columbia agrees to change in capital stock structure.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Directors, Officers, 1939-1959 (Box 86, Folder 651)
    Lists of directors and officers; tributes to directors upon death or retirement.
    205.10A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) - National Broadcasting Company, 1929-1938 (Box 87, Folder 652)
    Initial tenancy rules for Radio-Keith-Orpheum in Opera block; plans for Radio City; construction. Tentative cancellation plans; reduction in space occupied. Management of theaters. Correspondents include E. W. Harden, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, H. Robertson, David Sarnoff.
    205.11
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) - National Broadcasting Company - FOX Contract, 1935-1936 (Box 87, Folder 653)
    Arrangements for films for Music Hall.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) - National Broadcasting Company - Group Insurance, 1937 (Box 87, Folder 654)
    Copy of plan for theater employees.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) - National Broadcasting Company - RKO Contract, 1938-1939 (Box 87, Folder 655)
    Arranging of exhibition terms.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) - National Broadcasting Company - United Artists Contract, 1935 (Box 87, Folder 656)
    Discussion of exhibition policies.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) - National Broadcasting Company - W. G. Van Schumus - Personal, 1940-1943 (Box 87, Folder 657)
    Sickness; deach. Care of widow.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio Corporation Agreements, 1930-1932 (Box 87, Folder 658)
    Copies of printed agreements.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio Corporation Agreements, 1933-1934 (Box 87, Folder 659)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio Corporation Agreements - Lease Agreement - Music Halls, 1934 (Box 87, Folder 660)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall and Center Theater, 1931-1937 (Box 88, Folder 661)
    Felicitations on opening night; comments on theaters; suggestions for shows. Requests for jobs; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on Music Hall; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. address to Music Hall staff, 1937. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, W. G. Van Schmus, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    205.11A
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall and Center Theater, 1938-1945 (Box 88, Folder 662)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall and Center Theater, 1946-1961 (Box 88, Folder 663)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall and Center Theater - S. L. Rothafel Correspondence, 1931-1940 (Box 88, Folder 664)
    Roxy's plans; resignation.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall and Center Theater - G. S. Eyssell, 1942-1949 (Box 88, Folder 665)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest in Music Hall.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall and Center Theater - Floors Plans of Theatres (Box 88, Folder 666)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall Corporation, 1936-1961 (Box 88, Folder 667)
    Minutes of directors meetings; changes in directors; financial policies. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Sarnoff, Gus Eyssell.
    205.11A1
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio City Music Hall Corporation - Lease, 1936-1950 (Box 88, Folder 668)
    Music Hall lease from Rockefeller Center, Inc..
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Center Theater, 1934-1938 (Box 89, Folder 669)
    Search for profitable use for theater; John D. Rockefeller 3rd on Theater Committee; use as television studio. Demolition.
    205.11C1
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Center Theater, 1939-1954 (Box 89, Folder 670)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Center Theater - Virginia, 1937-1950 (Box 89, Folder 671)
    Musical comedy at Center Theater - faded.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Center Theater - The American Way, 1938-1940 (Box 89, Folder 672)
    Comments on show.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Center Theater - Radio Corporation of America (RCA) Television Studio, 1950 (Box 89, Folder 673)
    Lease arrangements.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Center Theater - It Happens On Ice, 1941-1946 (Box 89, Folder 674)
    Shift to ice shows in Theater; comments on stage design; cancellation of Ice-A-Poppin' Plans in 1940. Correspondents include Hugh Robertson.
    205.11C2
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Claim and Receivership, 1933-1938 (Box 90, Folder 675)
    Rockefeller Center, Inc. claim against Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) when RKO went into receivership and failed to occupy space in Rockefeller Center, amounted to $9,000,000. Rockefeller Center, Inc. took stock in reorganized RKO company to adjust claim. Rockefeller Center, Inc. and Radio Corporation interests in managing RKO; relations between Rockefellers and Atlas Corporation; financing of RKO. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Nelson A. Rockefeller, H. Robertson, John R. Todd, Floyd Odlum.
    205.11D
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Claim and Receivership, 1939-1943 (Box 90, Folder 676)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Claim and Receivership - J. F. Parsons Letters, 1938-1941 (Box 90, Folder 677)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. guaranteed that J. F. Parsons wouldn't be held in anti-trust suit as director of Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO).
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Claim and Receivership - J. F. Parsons Arrangement, 1940-1942 (Box 90, Folder 678)
    Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Director for Rockefeller Center, Inc. paid by Rockefeller Center, Inc.; asked to resign in 1941.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) Claim and Receivership - George Schafer, 1938-1943 (Box 90, Folder 679)
    Hired as President of Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO); his tenure, opposition, resignation.
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) vs. Radio City, 1938 (Box 90, Folder 680)
    Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO) suit against Music Hall for rejecting some RKO films; no final settlement here. Correspondents include Peter Rathvon, W. G. Van Schmus, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Floyd Odlum.
    205.11E
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. - Radio-Keith-Orpheum (RKO), 1939-1944 (Box 90, Folder 681)